<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>sensor fusion | Zida&#39; Homepage</title>
    <link>https://zidawu.github.io/tags/sensor-fusion/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://zidawu.github.io/tags/sensor-fusion/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>sensor fusion</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2019 Zida Wu</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://zidawu.github.io/img/icon-192.png</url>
      <title>sensor fusion</title>
      <link>https://zidawu.github.io/tags/sensor-fusion/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multi-sensor Fusion for Inspection Robot</title>
      <link>https://zidawu.github.io/project/msf-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://zidawu.github.io/project/msf-project/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;To deploy the autonomous robot into reality,  where the robots have to cope with complicated and challenging environment, it is a tendency that fusing multi-sensor data to achieve the target. Besides, the calibration, time synchronization and computation complexity should also be came into considered. This projects introduced a loose-coupled framework that fuses IMU, SLAM, GNSS and other sensors separately, which tolerates single sensor signal lost during operation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The algorithm allowed each sensor to separately estimate their own pose, and conducted the relative-absolute relationship, for example the IMU-SLAM or SLAM-GPS. Then it would apply error-state KF to optimize the independent poses from SLAM and IMU, and fed back into the nominal state to acquire the genuine pose.  In this process,  the rigid constraint between the local world and vision frame should be loosed since the gravity gradually calibrate the frame into the gravity-alignment coordinate. After that, A second error-state filter is utilized to fuse the GNSS measurements to prevent state estimation drift in long-term operation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition, this algorithm synchronization strategy is to interpolate single sensor measurements to the closest state in the queue.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
