<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>PDR | Zida&#39; Homepage</title>
    <link>https://zidawu.github.io/tags/pdr/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://zidawu.github.io/tags/pdr/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>PDR</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2019 Zida Wu</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://zidawu.github.io/img/icon-192.png</url>
      <title>PDR</title>
      <link>https://zidawu.github.io/tags/pdr/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>High-accuracy GNSS Positioning on Portable Smartphone</title>
      <link>https://zidawu.github.io/project/gnss-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://zidawu.github.io/project/gnss-project/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Google released Android Nougat (version 7.0) in 2016, which opens the possibility to use raw data to achieve high precision  solutions on low-cost smart devices. Due to the poor performance of the low-cost antenna and crystal oscillator of smartphone,  the accuracy of traditional single point positioning can only reach about 10 meters. However, IMU, the interoceptive sensor which never care about the interference outside, enable to assit GNSS to achieve robust and continous localization.  Therefore, this project aimed to develop an algorithm which achieved high-accuracy and reliable positioning of smartphones under complex environment using GNSS-IMU fusion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We developed an Android application to obatin the raw GNSS chips data and parsed it into generic format RINEX 3.02. During the analysis, we found that phone horrible oscillator existed intermittent 256ns drift. Then the pseudorange double-difference (PDD) was perforemd to eliminate the atmosphere, satellite, and phone clock error, as well as decoupled the pseudorange and velocity measurements based on the short-baseline hypothesis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, the joint heading estimation using Pedestrian Dead Reckoning (PDR) and GNSS Doppler was also presented, the result showes that this algorithm calibrated the PDR gait length loss and heading drift in the long-term, and maintained the high smooth and accuracy in the short-term.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
